Rup Gautam

Toronto • rupngautam@gmail.com • 971-221-0659 • in/rupgautam • rupgautam.github.io

SUMMARY

Site Reliability Engineer with over 5 years of experience scaling large-scale production infrastructure. I've driven reliability efforts, including monitoring, alerting, automated deployment pipelines, and failure resiliency. Experienced in AWS cloud, Continuous Integration & Continuous deployment (CI-CD), Configuration Management, and Infrastructure automation (Ansible, Terraform).

EXPERIENCE

Site Reliability Engineer | DISQO INC.

November 2020 - Present, Los Angeles, California

- Maintaining Infrastructure as code and setting up of Kubernetes cluster and services on AWS.
- Designing and implementing CI / CD pipelines for a range of microservices leveraging the use of GitLab CI and ArgoCD to ship at speed.
- Driving reliability efforts, including adding monitoring, alerting, deployment practices, and resiliency. This effort significantly increased the percentage of critical infrastructure teams that had effective monitoring and alerting.
- Lead post-mortem incident reviews to identify the root cause analysis and ensure remediation, and created a process for write-ups of incident learnings that could be communicated broadly throughout DISQO.
- Improved our "Security posture" effort from scratch to 75% improvement and made it ready for SOC1.
- Onboarded security tools such as: Rapid7 Insight VM, Lacework, Crowdstrike, etc. at larger scale.

DevOps Engineer | Encircle Inc.

November 2019 - February 2020, Kitchener, ON

- Maintained deployment and staging server environment in Azure/AWS.
- Ansible to automate deployment of various application to production servers.
- Managed environments DEV, QA, STAGING and PRODUCTION servers for various releases.
- Phabricator to manage issues/PR/Code-Reviews, include creating weekly sprints.
- Performed Unit tests, Selenium, automatic screenshots, load tests for internal applications.

DevOps Engineer | Osorno Enterprises

Sept 2017 - November 2019, Winnipeg, MB

- Terraform and Ansible-Playbooks to managed AWS/GCP infrastructure (Infrastructure as code).
- \bullet Managed AWS services: EC2, EBS, ELB, SSL, Security Groups, RDS and IAM etc.
- Used Jenkins tool to automate the build process for 15+ services.
- Deployed builds for various environments such as: DEV, QA, STAGING and PRODUCTION servers.
- Configured and monitored distributed and multi-platform servers and applications using Grafana/Prometheus/Datadog.

System Administrator | Osorno Enterprises

June 2017 - Sept 2017, Winnipeg, MB

- Supported 25+ Linux/Windows servers in the production/QA/Development environment.
- Automated Linux servers deployment using Ansible and bash.
- Deployed a highly available ELK and Prometheus stack for monitoring.
- Maintain and configured NFS, DNS, DHCP, LDAP, AD, and iSCSI servers.
- Maintain networked highly available GlusterFS for data storage.

EDUCATION

Post Graduate Program in DevOps (Online) | California Institute of Technology

Online Program, Sept 2020 - July 2021

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | University of Winnipeg

Sept 2017 - Jan 2020

CERTIFICATIONS

Kubernetes for Developers CKAD | The Linux Foundation 2022

SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks: Python, Bash, YAML, Node, JavaScript, Ant, Maven, Gradle.

Clouds and Containers: AWS, Azure, GCP, Docker, Packer, Vagrant.
Automation tools: Terraform, Ansible, CloudFormation, Bash.
CI Tools: Gitlab, Jenkins, Bamboo, Octopus, Github Action, CircleCI.

er roots. Ortiab, serikins, bamboo, octopus, ortilab Action, ericicei.

Monitoring Tool: Grafana, Collectd, Grafite, Kibana, Opsgenie, Cloud watch, Splunk, Datadog.

PROJECTS

K8s Blue Green Deployment | https://github.com/RupGautam/k8s-blue-green-deployment Nov 2020

Python Flask CRUD Application | https://github.com/RupGautam/py-flask-ansible-docker July 2020